Like I say, welcome brothers and sisters
to another Wednesday Q&A where we open
up with the Ten Commandments that God
commanded for the whole world to keep.
Brother James.
>> Yes, sir. And God spake all these words,
saying, I am the Lord thy God, which
have brought thee out of the land of
Egypt, out of the house of bondage. Thou
shalt have no other gods before me. Thou
shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above, or that is in the
earth beneath, or that is in the water
under the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God, am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Sixth day shalt thou labor
and do all thy work, but the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work. Thou thou
thy not thy son, nor thy daughter, thy
man's servant, nor thy maidervant, nor
thy cattle, nor thy stranger that is
within thy gates. For in six days the
Lord made heaven and earth, the sea, and
all that in them is, and restth the
seventh day. Wherefore the Lord blessed
the Sabbath day, and hollowed it. Honor
thy father and thy mother, that thy days
may be long upon the land which the Lord
thy God giveth thee. Thou shalt not
kill. Thou shalt not commit adultery.
Thou shalt not steal. Thou shalt not
bear false witness against thy neighbor.
Thou shalt not co cover covet thy
neighbor's house. Thou shalt not covet
thy neighbor's wife, nor as man's
servant, nor as maid's servant, nor as
ox, nor as ass, nor anything that is thy
neighbors. I read Exodus 20:es 1-17.
May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of this word. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague and long
scripture questions as well as questions
of debate. We are not here to debate. We
are here to spread the true gospel of
Jesus. So, please be as direct as
possible with your questions so we can
be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you keep them to a two
scripture maximum. But let me introduce
to you the family that's on the panel
this evening. We got brother Dre. Good
evening.
>> Brother Jerome,
>> grace and peace.
>> Brother Julius,
>> good evening everybody.
>> Brother James,
>> good evening everyone.
>> Sister Deborah,
>> good evening.
>> Brother Sean,
>> And we have the guest caller with us.
And I'm brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question of the
evening? Uh yes, there are several held
over questions that will be answered
first before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Uh we're going to revisit Detroit price
question. He says in Exodus 12 verse8
and Ezekiel 45
21,
how do we get 8 days from the 14 day to
the 21st day of the month?
>> All right.
>> So, we're going to ask the guest caller
to shed some light on that question.
>> Okay. you know uh uh in order to get
that show this we have to uh uh go back
and read where it's in the first chapter
of uh uh Genesis where it says the
evening and the morning is the first
day. So so we talking evening and
morning is the first day. Let's let's go
back Genesis 1 and one and and so we can
establish that
and we can start uh uh uh starting when
God created light.
>> Okay.
And
>> starting at Genesis uh 1 and1, in the
beginning God created the heaven and the
earth. And the earth was without form
and void, and darkness was upon the face
of the deep. And and the spirit of God
moved upon the face of the waters. And
God said, "Let there be light." And
there was light. And God saw the light
that it was good. And God divided the
light from the darkness. And God called
the light day and the darkness he called
night and the evening and the morning
were the first day.
Now this is what I want to establish
that when you went on if you keep read
don't need to read all of that it keep
telling you and the evening and the
morning was the second day and the
evening and the morning was the third
day. So, I had answered this question uh
uh uh last week and it was in an error
cuz I said the 14th. I said the end of
the 14th, but being that the Bible
mentioned the 14th, you have to start at
the beginning of the 14th. So, now we
going to use some simple math
uh uh for the on the the evening and the
morning. Uh uh that's the 14th.
Then when you go to evening in the
morning, that's the 15th. Evening in the
morning is the 16th. Evening in the
morning is the 17th. The evening in the
morning is the 18th. The evening and the
morning is the 19th. The evening in the
morning is the 20th. And the evening and
the morning is the 21st. Now, if you
count that, so the 14th, evening
morning, that's one day.
And then the uh uh 15th that's 2 days.
16th that's 3 days.
17th that's 4 days. The 18th that's 5
days. And the uh uh 19th that's six uh
uh uh uh
let me see. I lost my count.
>> The 19th is the sixth day, sir.
>> Okay. the uh 19th is the sixth day and
the uh uh and the uh 20th is the seventh
day and the 21st is the eighth day cuz
you have to count the whole day because
the evening and the morning makes up the
day. So that's how we get eight days
because uh uh you can't go from uh uh
from one to two and and and and between
one and two is one day. That was the
error that I did last week. The whole
day. So, uh uh so the 14 is a day, the
15 is a day, the 16 is a day, the 17 is
a day, 18 is a day, and the 19 is a day,
the 20 is a day, and the 21st is a day.
So that's eight days. Okay.
>> Yep. Good.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right.
So, we thank you for that answer there.
We hope that answered their question and
we're going to move on to our next one.
>> Yes. Next one.
>> Let me say this right quick. You had
seven days of of of uh unleaven bread
and then then you had the Passover which
is the 14th. Then it said too, you
should not have no living bread with
that either with that lamb of the first
year. So that's why you can get your
eight days, seven unleven bread and one
Passover, but it all unleaven bread. You
eat unleaven bread.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. All right. We're going to move on
to our next question.
>> Next one. Be alert. Would like you to
explain the difference between first
fruits and Pentecostals.
He also or also warns you to explain
Leviticus
23 verse 17 and 18. The two loaves and
seven lambs without blemish.
Uh they want to know the significant of
those things.
>> All right, brother Jerome. The
significance of those things.
Well, the um first fruits is is is
talking about Jesus Christ.
And
when you talking about the
Pentecost, which is 50, that's pretty
much dealing with the uh two lows, which
is the first and second resurrection.
>> [clears throat]
>> But the um
the feast days that you that you that we
read about in that Leviticus the 23rd
chapter chapter that's the plan of God
for salvation and Jesus Christ is an
intricral part of that salvation. And so
um a lot of these different customs
associated with the feast point in some
in some cases to Jesus and we gonna show
you. Uh, so let's go to that Leviticus
the 23rd chapter. Pick it up at verse
10. Read it to the 12.
>> Leviticus 23:10
says, "Speak unto the children of
Israel, and say unto them, when ye be
come into the land which I give unto
you, and shall reap the harvest thereof,
then ye shall bring a sheath of the
first fruit of your harvest unto the
priest.
And he shall wave the sheep before the
Lord to be accepted for you. And on the
tomorrow after the Sabbath, the priest
shall wave it. And ye shall offer that
day when ye wave the sheep and he lamb
without blemish of the first year for a
burnt offering unto the Lord.
>> Okay? And that represent Jesus. He he
the he
the first fruit without blemish. Okay?
of the harvest.
All right. So, uh let's connect that
with 1 Corinthians chapter 15. Hold your
place in that Leviticus 23. We going to
come back.
>> Okay.
>> Go to 1 Corinthians 15. Read verse 20 to
23.
>> Okay. 1 Corinthians 15 20- 23 says, "But
now is Christ risen from the dead and
become the first fruits of them that
slept. For since by man came death, by
man came also the resurrection of the
dead. For as in Adam all die, even so in
Christ shall all be made alive.
But every man in his own order, Christ
the first fruit, afterward they that are
Christ at his coming.
>> Okay? So Christ is the first fruits of
those that going to be resurrected from
the dead. That's the harvest. You're the
first fruit. All right. So now let's go
back to that Leviticus
and we going to pick it up at 15.
Read it to the 17. Okay. It says, "And
ye shall count unto you from the
tomorrow after the Sabbath, from the day
that ye brought the sheath of the waif
offering, seven Sabbaths shall be
complete."
>> Mhm.
>> Even until the tomorrow after the
seventh Sabbath shall ye number 50 days,
and ye shall offer a new meat offering
unto the Lord.
Ye shall bring out of your habitations
two wave loaves of two tenth deals. They
shall be a fine flower. They shall be
bacon with leaven. They are the first
fruits of the L on unto the Lord.
>> Uh-huh. So now remember the harvest is
the resurrection first and second. All
right. So now we talking about us and
it's baking with levan because we had
sin which Jesus you know he he had to
cover. All right. So we we represent the
two wave loads the first resurrection
and the second resurrection. Okay. Uh in
that 50th year of Pentecost that's when
we going to get waved before the father
to be accepted. Okay. Now, um, read that
18 cuz you know Jesus, he was the first
fruit and he didn't have no levvenant
with him. But with us, the two loaves,
we had the leaven. That's what that
baked with leaven represent. It
represent the scene. Okay. All right. So
read that verse 18. And ye shall offer
with the bread seven lambs without
blemish of the first year, and one one
young bullock, and two rams. They shall
be for a burnt offering unto the Lord,
with their meat offering, and their
drink offerings, even an offering made
by fire of sweet savor unto the Lord.
>> Okay? And now the seven lambs that
represent Jesus. And he's covering the
sins of
obedient believers, okay? For the 7,000
years that God gave this man
to to be in these flesh and blood
bodies. Cuz after them 7,000 years,
ain't going to be no more man. It ain't
going to be no more death. Every all all
man gonna be spirit beings after that.
Okay? So Jesus with these seven lambs
represent him covering this the sins of
obedient believers for them full 7,000
years that God gave this man to operate
in these flesh and blood bodies. That's
that's all I got on.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we continue to move on to our next
question.
>> Moving on. Lita Mlin
uh asks, "Is it a sin to celebrate
birthdays?"
In Genesis 49, excuse me, in Genesis 40
verse 20 and Mark 6 verse 21, the
birthdays both seem to end in tragedy.
Can you please help me understand?
All right, your first part of that
question about is it sin to celebrate
your birthday, the answer is no. But
when you celebrate your birthday, you
should always have the commandments of
God in mind. But let's go into Genesis
40 and because this is uh where a lot of
people go to say that you shouldn't
celebrate your birthday. It's evil if
you do. But we're going to read about
Pharaoh here. And we're going to see
that Pharaoh made a choice on his own
birthday. So, let's go and read that
Genesis 40 and let's pick it up,
brother, at that verse um
20.
Okay, it says, "And it came to pass the
third day, which was Pharaoh's birthday,
that he made a feast unto all his
servants, and he lifted up the head of
the chief butler and of the chief baker
among his servants."
>> All right. So, he hung that uh that
chief baker right there. Go ahead.
and he restored the chief butler unto
his butlership again, and he gave the
cup into Pharaoh's hand.
>> But he hanged the chief baker as Joseph
has interpreted it to them.
>> All right. So, Pharaoh made a choice. He
hung the chief baker on his birthday.
The other question was Mark 6. Let's go
to Mark 6 right quick.
>> Okay.
and we'll read about another choice
here.
So, you have choices on what you can do
for your birthday, but always stay
within the dos and don'ts of thus says
the Lord.
Mark 6.
And when you get there, brother, let's
pick it up.
Let's pick it up. Read 18 and 19. Let's
just get a little a little story here
before we get to the birthday part. Mark
6:18 and 19. Go ahead.
>> For John had said unto Herod, "It is not
lawful for thee to have thy brother's
wife."
>> That's what got John in trouble there,
telling Herod what thus says the Lord as
far as the commandments is concerned. Go
ahead. 19.
>> Therefore, Herodiius had a quarrel
against him and would have killed him,
but she could not.
>> Right. This is the woman here who John
was telling her telling uh Herod that he
could not have which was Herodiius
because that was his brother's wife.
Skip down to verse 21 and read.
>> And when a convenient day was come that
Herod on his birthday made a supper to
his lords high captains and chief
estates to Galilee.
>> Go ahead. And when the daughter of the
said Herodiius came in and danced, and
please Herod and them that sat with him,
the king said unto the damsel, "Ask of
me whatsoever thou wilt, and I will give
it thee."
>> So this is Herodia's daughter that came
um and the daughter came to her, and she
danced before Herod, pleased him, and
then he said, "Hey, whatever you want,
I'll give it to you. Go ahead.
And he swear unto her, whatsoever thou
shalt ask of me, I will give it thee
unto the half of my kingdom.
>> Yeah.
>> And she went forth and said unto her
mother, what shall I ask? And she said,
the head of John the Baptist.
>> Right? So Herodiius, her mother said,
hey, look, ask for the head of John the
Baptist. Because as we read in that
verse 19, she would have killed John
herself if it was within her power to do
so. But she used her daughter on that.
Now let's see the choice that Herod made
on his birthday. Verse 27.
And immediately the king sent an
executioner
and commanded his head to be brought.
And he went and beheaded him in the
prison.
>> Mhm.
>> And brought his head in a charger and
gave it to the damsel. And the damsel
gave it to her mother.
>> Yep. So you see John the Baptist got
beheaded because Herodius didn't like
the fact that
John had said to Herod that you cannot
have your brother's wife and a and did
we read that verse 21? We read that.
>> Yes, we did.
>> Okay. So it was on Herod's birthday that
he chose to do this act here. So final
place 1 John 3 and 4. 1 John 3 and4.
>> 1 John 3 and4 says, "Whosoever
committeth sin transgresseth also the
law for sin is the transgression of the
law."
>> Right? So if you want to celebrate your
birthday and keep the law of God because
you have to celebrate your birthday and
if you like to do so no breaking of the
law of God because sin is a
transgression of the law.
>> And that's all I got on that.
>> Brother Cornel,
>> I like that.
>> Yes,
>> Oh, okay.
>> You go back.
where he talk about the one that he
killed, but what about the one that he
restored to his image?
>> That's verse.
>> You see what I'm saying?
>> That's verse 21.
>> Uhhuh.
>> That that says that says, "And he
restored the chief butler unto his
butlership again, and he gave the cup
into Pharaoh's hand."
>> Now, now, okay, then. So this guy was
restored.
>> Yeah.
>> But you had one that was beheaded.
>> Now John the Baptist. Sure. It was
Herod's birthday. But then the Bible
say, "Oh Jerusalem, Jerusalem that kleth
the prophet and stone those that are
sent to you." That's what Jesus said.
How many times I will gather you like a
motherhead and gather a chick? But you
were not. So you going to tell me every
prophet that was killed was on
somebody's birthday?
Mhm.
That's what I'm saying. Those are
incidents that seem to happen like that,
but it got nothing to do with your
birthday.
>> Exactly.
>> Yeah.
>> Both birthdays. Both. Go ahead, guest
caller.
>> You know, blessed is the day that Jesus
was born.
>> You understand?
>> Yes.
>> Oh, yeah.
Do not when you c celebrate a birthday
what's this got to do with good or bad
it was a coincidence just happened one
of them you had good and a bad thing
happened on his birthday but then all
the but if that's the occasion then all
the prophets that was killed should not
have been killed except for on the
birthdays
>> and Israel killed all the just about all
the prophets Yeah,
>> that's true.
>> Yeah.
>> Both
>> both birthdays ending in tragedy has
nothing to do with your personal choice
of celebrating your birthday or not.
>> Has nothing to do that is a personal
choice.
>> It is not It is not sin. Long as you
don't sin against God on your birthday,
you good.
>> Sin is a transgression of the law. Just
like Corell read.
All right.
>> Praise the Lord. So, we hope that that
has shed some light and kind of brought
an end to that question being asked. All
right. We're going to move on to our
next one.
>> Moving on. Sky Rider asks, "What was the
2300 day prophecy about? Did it mean
2300 years? And does it have anything to
do with an investigative judgment?"
>> Judgement. All right. Just call it a
2300 day prophecy.
What what you say?
>> No, it's not 2300 years and didn't have
no in investigative prophecy. That was a
time
let's let's let's uh uh go back and look
at it. I think it's Revelations, not
Revelation, Daniel the 8th chapter.
And we going to
This is the [clears throat] eighth
chapter. And let's look at the where he
said that uh uh uh uh when the angel
asked him how long. We start at verse
one. 8 and one. We're going to read into
it.
>> Okay.
>> In the third year of the reign of King
Belshazar, a vision appeared unto me,
even unto me Daniel, after that which
appeared unto me at the first.
And I saw in a vision and it came to
pass when I saw that I was at Shushan in
the palace which is in the province of
Elam. And I saw in a vision and I was by
the river of Uliot.
Then I lifted up my eyes and saw and
behold there stood before the river a
ram which had two horns. And the two
horns were high, but one was higher than
the other, and the higher came up last.
>> Okay, we can't read.
>> We not going to read all that.
>> We skip down to where the one asking
when he saw he asked, "How long would
this be going on?" Because this is
talking about the uh uh uh uh uh when
the what uh uh when the Gentiles was
ruling. And then you come up with this
one ruler that magnified himself unto
the Lord. And and uh uh and one angel
asked the other, "How long will this
be?"
>> Verse 13. 13 and 14.
>> I'll read it. Verse 13 says, "Then I
heard one saint speaking, and another
saint said unto that certain saint,
which spake, how long shall be the
vision concerning the daily sacrifice,
and the transgression of desolation, to
give both the sanctuary and the host to
be trotten underfoot?"
And he said unto uh So now he was
talking about how long is he going to
have a day of sacrifice? you know,
that's that's uh that's prior uh uh uh
to the time that Jesus is going to be
coming and also to give the the ho the
des the host of to uh uh the sanctuary
to the desolation. That's talking about
the abomination that desolation. And
what did he say? How long shall this be?
Go ahead. Verse 14, he said, "And he
said unto me, unto 2,300
days, then shall the sanctuary be
cleansed."
Okay. So now the 2300 days, so you have
uh uh um you have the great
tribulations,
that's 1260 days.
>> Yeah.
And then you have the and so and you
take the 1260 days
uh uh which equal to 3 and a2 years from
the 2300 days and you got 1,00 and uh uh
uh 40 days. That's a little over that's
a little under uh uh 3 years.
So what happened is the great
tribulation is going to cause uh uh is
going to go on for three and a half
years.
That's when they going to be polluting
the sanctuary cuz the abomination of
desolation is going to be standing in
the holy place. And so and but before he
take over they going to be sacrificing
animals in Jerusalem.
So what's going to happen is the
abomination of desolation going to stop
daily sacrifice which is tw which is 140
days. What's that about a little over
two years?
>> Yeah. A little over two years and then
once he stopped that he is going to
stand in the hold the place and rule for
three and a half years. So we're talking
about a little less than uh uh uh seven
years all together. So it's not 2300
years, it's 2,300 days. Those are the
days that the beast and that they going
to sacrifice animals in Jerusalem. And
then the pope going to leave from Rome
and he going to stop the animal
sacrifice and he going to rule for three
and a half years of great tribulation
all together just a little less than uh
a little uh uh uh less than four years.
So no, so just letting you know the
great that they they're going to start
animal sacrifice when they sacrifice the
first animal in Jerusalem.
You can start that count because that is
the beginning of the end. And that
extend to the last day of the great
tribulation which is the day that the
Lord come and take the beast and throws
prophet down and put them in the lake of
fire which you get in Revelation the
19th chapter. So that's what it's
called. That that's just talking about
the time of the great tribulation and
the time of the animal sacrifice.
They all together is a little less than
7 years which is 2300 [clears throat]
days.
That's all I have to add to say.
>> Right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answers your question as we move on to
our next one.
>> Next one. Kylie Parker says in First
Timothy 2 verse8 it says pray without
doubt and wrath. I'm a bit confused on
the wrath part. If I'm praying for help
in a situation of wickedness and I'm
angry while I while in the prayer, am I
in error?
>> All right. 1 Timothy 2:8 and praying
while you are angry. Brother Dre, what
you say?
>> Let's go read 1 Timothy 2:8 and then
we're going somewhere else after that.
>> Go ahead and read it, James. When you
get it,
>> it says, "I will therefore that men pray
everywhere, lifting up holy hands
without wrath and doubting."
>> So he's saying without wrath and
doubting. And that's what the question
that you have is. Let's go to Ephesians
4 and let's uh read verses 26 and 27.
Ephesians 4 26 and 27.
>> It says, "Be ye angry and sin not. Let
not the sun go down upon your wrath,
neither give place to the devil."
So don't don't be angry and sin not. Uh
and don't give place to the devil. But
why is this being said? Let's go to Mark
11 and we going to look at it here and
this should wrap it up. Mark 11:24-26.
Go ahead. Mark 11 Mark 11:24-
26 says, "Therefore I say unto you, what
things soever ye desire when ye pray,
believe that ye receive them, and ye
shall have them."
>> So we talking about praying here. Go
ahead.
And when ye stand praying, forgive if ye
have ought against any, that your father
also which is in heaven may forgive you
your trespasses.
>> Mhm.
>> But if ye do not forgive, neither will
your father which is in heaven forgive
your trespasses.
>> And that is why in the Lord's prayer it
says, forgive us our debts as we forgive
our debtors. So when we go to pray, we
shouldn't come praying in anger towards
a situation.
And so this scripture right here, what
Jesus is saying when you when you go to
pray that for the things you desire,
forgive if you got a against any that
your father also which is in heaven may
forgive you your trespasses.
That's all I got.
All right, good light there, brother. As
we continue to move on with the time
check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:05. Kylie Parker also
asks, "What was
what was abolished and what does it mean
by their minds were blinded?"
Second Corinians 3 12-4
are given.
All right, brother Julius.
Okay, Deborah, let's let's revisit that
question as we keep moving.
>> Yes. Uh the next one Sky Rider asks,
"What does
pray that your flight not be in the
winter or on the Sabbath mean?"
All right, let's let's go to uh that
Matthews
Matthews the 24th chapter
because this is all during the same
time,
Matthew's 24.
And let's pick it up at that verse 15
because this is going to be the kicking
off of the great tribulation and you'll
be needing to go east and they keep the
some of those places over there keep the
Sabbath and honor the Sabbath and um
might be a little tough to be getting
around but Matthew 24:15 go ahead.
When ye therefore shall see the
abomination of desolation spoken of by
Daniel the prophet stand in the holy
place, whosoever readeth, let him
understand.
>> All right? So this is when the
abomination and make it desolate is
going to stand in the holy place. You
have to flee and you have to get to the
place of safety. And skip down to verse
20 and go ahead, brother.
but praying that your flight be not in
the winter, neither on the Sabbath day.
>> Yes. Cuz it'd be tough sometimes to
travel in the winter. Never know how the
weather going to treat you. And um and
on the Sabbath day, some places over
there will be keeping the Sabbath. So
they shut down some and it might be hard
to get around. So you just pray that
when it's time to go that it's not in
the winter and not on the Sabbath day.
But if it happen to be, the Lord always
makes a way. Verse 21.
>> For then shall be great tribulation,
such as was not since the beginning of
the world to this time, no, nor ever
shall be.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And except those days should be
shortened, there should no flesh be
saved, but for the elect's sake, those
days shall be shortened.
>> Right? So that's why you want to make
sure that you know you just pray that
your flight don't be in the winter or on
the Sabbath day. And if you want a
little more understanding of that great
tribulation and the place of safety, we
do have a a lesson on that called the
wilderness, the place of safety during
great tribulation. And that will help to
shed even more light on this situation
for you. But that's all I got.
All right. So, Sister Deborah, let's uh
step back up and revisit that question
so we can bring our brother Julius in.
>> All right. Uh, Kylie Parker also asks,
"What was abolished and what does it
mean by their minds were blinded?" 2
Corinians 3 12-14
are given.
>> All right. Apolished and their minds
were blinded. Brother Julius,
>> my apologies. I spill something. Let's
go to that scripture. Let's go to the
scripture and and read it. Uh, brother
James.
>> Okay. uh 2 Corinthians 3
12-4 say,
"Seeing then that we have such hope, we
use great [clears throat] plainness of
speech,
and not as Moses, which put a veil over
his face, that the children of Israel
could not steadfastly look to the end of
that which is abolished."
But their minds were blinded. For until
this day remainth the same veil untaken
away in the reading of the Old Testament
which veil is done away in Christ.
All right. The definition of the word
abolished to mean is to be to completely
do away with something or someone. So
this right here has to do with the
abolishing of the flesh and blood body.
>> How will it how will it be abolished?
Let's go to 1 Corinthians the 15th
chapter and then we going to do the
other part of this question. 1
Corinthians the 15th chapter, brother
James.
>> Okay,
>> pick it up at verse 35. 1 Corinthians 15
and35. We're talking about bodies. Go
ahead.
>> But some men will say, "How are the dead
raised up? And with what body do they
come?"
>> Skip all the way down. We're talking
bodies now. 42 to 44. Go ahead.
>> So also is the resurrection of the dead.
>> Uhhuh.
>> It is sown in corruption.
>> Yes.
>> It is raised in incorruption.
>> It is sown a fle It is sown uh brought
forth in flesh and blood. It is raised a
spiritual body. That mean that the flesh
and blood is done away with. Continue.
>> It is sown in dishonor. It is raised in
glory. It is sown in weakness. It is
raised in power.
>> When you come out that grave, you going
to have a glorious body with power. If
you so were blessed. Verse 44.
>> It is sown a natural body. It is raised
a spiritual body.
>> Uh-huh.
>> There is a natural body and there is a
spiritual body.
spiritual body. As we have born there,
let the book talk. 49. Go ahead.
And as we have borne the image of the
earthy, we shall also bear the image of
the heavenly
>> man.
So now
as we have borne as we have borne the
image of the earth and that's a flesh
and blood body. When the Lord come away
and do away with this flesh and blood,
you going to have a spiritual body. That
mean that this flesh and blood will be
abolished. Now that means done away with
because it is sown in weakness and is
raised in power. Now let's go back.
Let's go back brother to 2 Corinthians 3
and 2 Corinthians 3 and we going to read
the other half of that. Verse 14.
But their minds were blinded for until
this day remainth the same veil untaken
away in the reading of the Old Testament
which veil is done away in Christ. So
now why would they it says that their
mind was blinded that mean that they
could not understand or comprehend
prophecy scripture
they couldn't understand these things
that's why the Lord that's why we keep
reading the word of God and the Holy
Ghost will re reveal his word to us
sisters and brothers let's go to 2
Corinthians 4 Corinthians 4 we going to
read just three or four and done.
Remember that could the pure children of
Israel Moses came. He went up into the
mountain was up there with the Lord 40
days and 40 nights and came back and his
face began to shine. He began to take on
the form of an immortal. Immortal beings
and their full power shine like the
brightness of the sun. So he had to put
a veil over his face when he came down
and dealt with the children of Israel.
When he went into the sanctuary, he
talked to the Lord. He had to take the
veil off. They could not look at the end
of man. The end of man is God.
And whatever that be in the lake of
fire. Second Corinthians 4 and read
verse three and four. This is why their
mind was blinded. Go ahead.
>> But if our gospel be hid, it is hid to
them that are lost.
>> Uh-huh. in whom the God of this world
has blinded the minds of them which
believe not
>> because they don't have the faith.
Israel didn't have the faith to believe.
Go ahead. Least the light of the
glorious gospel of Christ who is the
image of God should shine onto them.
>> So therefore they could not their their
mind were blinded because they they
didn't have no faith. And so therefore,
sisters and brothers, their mind was
blinded. They couldn't understand
prophecy. They didn't understand the
thing that they was doing that was
hurting themselves. But Moses began to
take on the form of an immortal. So
therefore, they could not stand to look
at the end of man. The end of man is
God. And God and his glory and you and
your glory. When you get your glorified
body, glorified body, we will all shine.
And we're so blessed. That's all I got.
All right. Yes, sir. We all are looking
forward to that blessing, brother.
All right. We're going to move on to our
next question.
>> Moving on. Etica Masala says, "Reading
Job 33
14-16
and Proverbs 20 verse 24
means there is no such thing as free
will."
All right, we definitely need some light
on this free will, brother Dre.
>> Yeah. So, let's go to that job and we
going to read verses
14- 16. Go ahead and read it when you
get there, James.
>> Okay. It says, "For God speakest once,
yay, twice, yet man perceiveth not. in a
dream, in a vision of the night, when
deep sleep fallth upon men, and
slumberings upon the bed. Then he opened
the ears of men and seal sealth their
instruction.
>> So he give man instructions, right?
>> But but man has a choice about them
in-structions.
>> Skip down to verse 26.
He shall pray unto God, and he will be
favorable unto them, unto him, and he
shall see his face with joy, for he will
render unto man his righteousness.
>> Go ahead.
>> He lookth upon men, and if any say, I
have sinned, and perverted that which
was right, and it profited me not.
>> Mhm. He will deliver his soul from going
into the pit and his life shall see the
light.
>> So man can repent
and he could say I have sinned and
perverted that which was right and it
profited me not and the Lord will
deliver him. So he got a choice.
>> Go to that Proverbs 20 and 24.
>> Proverbs 20 and 24.
It says, "Man's goings are of the Lord."
How can a man then understand his own
way?
>> Hey, the Lord instructs us. We got a
choice. Now, let's go to the last place.
Let's go to Deuteronomy 30 and we going
to read verse 15 and skip.
Okay. It says,
"See, I have set before thee this day
life and good and death and evil."
>> So, he say, "I set before you this day
life and good and death and evil." Skip
down to verse uh 19 and read that. Go
ahead.
I call heaven and earth to record this
day against you that I have set before
you life and death, blessing and
cursing. Therefore, choose life that
both thou and thy seed may live.
>> So if you didn't have no free will to
choose, why is he telling you to choose
life here?
>> He said it before you. He gave you the
instructions and you make the choice.
And the and the choice that we all
should make is to choose life and live.
And those instructions are in his word
for us to abide in. And that's all I
got.
>> Yep. Because he say he command us to
love the Lord thy God with all our heart
and to walk in his ways.
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right, brother. Thank you for that.
I hope that answered that question as we
move on to our next
>> moving on. Charlotte T asks, "Is it a
sin to watch movies of any genre?
Hollywood seem to use wishcraft in their
movies to sway people to move contrary
to the word. But if you don't adhere to
what they push, are you sinning?"
All right, brother Julius
>> James, let's go back to first John 3 and
4. Sisters and brothers, we cannot make
everything sin. Sin is what the book
calls sin.
Sin. First John 3 and4. James, when you
get it, read it, please. According to
the Bible, look what sin is, sisters and
brothers.
Whosoever committeth sin transgresseth
also the law. For sin is the
transgression of the law.
>> Watching movies is not of any genre is
not sin. Witchcraft
is
is sin.
Cuz the Lord said there should be no
witches found among you. Now
let's let's look at where this come
from. You say Hollywood. Let's look at
who's behind Hollywood and who's behind
all sin. back to
back to uh 2 Corinthians 4 because this
applies
2 Corinthians 4 and4.
This is what sways people away. Go
ahead, brother.
In whom the God of this world hath
blinded the minds of them which believe
not, least the light of the glorious
gospel of Christ, who is the image of
God should shine unto them.
>> Now, say the devil is the god of this
world. That's a little G. He's the God
of this world. He controls Hollywood. He
controls the the internet, social media,
and everything. You know, all this
negativity that's going on. and uh uh
it's it's all in government and so on
and so forth. So
it watching uh movies of any genre is a
choice. It is what sometime you can't
blame the devil for what you do.
Sometime it's you and your choices when
you act upon them sisters and brothers.
So watching the movies of any genre is
not sin. Sin is a transgression of the
law. Now sometimes I watch these movies
myself to and then I look at the book
and everything is already written
because man lives by every word that
proceed out of the mouth of God. So
therefore sisters and brothers if I
don't watch them how could I identify
them with the book. Sometime you got to
watch things to identify with what's
going on according what's written. So
you can have understanding that the word
of God is absolutely true. So, no. If
you don't uh adhere to what they push,
are you sinning? No. That had nothing to
do with you. You're only sinning if you
participate and agree with witchcraft or
any other sin,
>> which is the transgression of the law.
That's all I got.
>> Yeah,
>> brother George, they just definitely
have to be careful of what they let
their children watch.
>> Yeah. Because the God of this world, he
is the enticer. He is the one that
pushes these things, pushes these
agenda, pushing this programming. You
don't see nothing. Everything. Why?
Because it is written times going to get
worse and worse and worse. So, we have
to guard our houses. We have to guard
everything, sisters and brother. Because
like the book say, as a waring lion,
Satan, the devil walk about seeking whom
he may devour. So therefore, he does it
by social media, by radio, television,
internet. As long as you don't
participate in on those things that are
against the word of God, hey, you good.
>> Yeah.
>> Watch what your children watch on their
TV as well as on their phones.
Make sure you are definitely guarding
them. All right. Hope that answered your
question. We're gonna move on to our
next one.
>> Next one. Stephen Guggis asks, "Are
there any scriptures that
are there any scriptures with how we are
to deal with children with mental
disabilities such as autism?"
>> All right, brother Dre. Our children
that have mental disabilities as well as
autism. Is there some scriptures to say
how that should be addressed?
>> Yeah, let's go over to uh Mark the 9th
chapter. autism uh
varies and it's a spectrum. Your your
child is on the spectrum. But I like how
the question is posed because we looking
at at how to deal with our children that
may be on the spectum a spectrum because
from day to day it may be different. It
may be extreme one day, not so extreme
the next day and we just got to make the
adjustments. But uh let's look at this
uh Mark 9 verse 21. Read that when you
get it, brother.
>> And he asks his father, "How long is it
ago since this came unto him?"
>> So he said,
>> Jesus is asking, "How long has it been
since this child has been suffering what
it's been suffering?" Go ahead.
>> And he said of a child. And he said is
he'd been suffering this since he was a
child. Skip down to verse 23. Go ahead.
>> And Jesus said unto him, "If thou can't
believe, all things are possible to him
that believeth."
>> Yeah. So, you know, he's asking for
healing for his son. And you know, with
with uh autism and being diagnosed on
the spectrum, we have to have a mindset
of how we're going to deal with our
children. And the book tells us how we
deal with them because this may be a
challenge to us from day to day. But
look at what the man said. Go ahead.
and and straightway the father of the
child cried out and said with
tears,"Lord,
I believe, help thou my unbelief." The
man said, "Lord, I believe, but help my
unbelief." So, he was seeking God on how
he should deal with those issues that he
may face on on the dayto day are looking
for healing for his problem. And the
Lord of course healed him. But let's go
to James because this may this is for
you. Let's go to James the first chapter
here.
>> James 1.
>> And I want you to pick it up at verse
two. James 1 and two. Go ahead. When you
get there, brother,
>> my brethren, count it all joy when ye
fall into diverse temptations. Now, you
know, don't nobody count stuff joy when
they going through all kind of problems.
So, I I hear it, you know, but at the
end of the day, your joy is going to
come. But there's something that you
have to do, and that's in the next
verse. Go ahead, brother.
>> Knowing this, that the trying of your
faith workketh patience.
>> So, this is what this is all about. the
patience that is working with you and
how you should approach dealing with
your child with autism or a child with
autism. Go ahead.
>> But let patience have her perfect work
that he may be perfect and entire
wanting nothing.
>> Now, what is this all about at the end
of the day? Skip down to verse 12. If
you endure this, this is what this is
about. Verse 12, go ahead.
>> Blessed is the man that endureth
temptation. For when he is tried, he
shall receive the crown of life, which
the Lord hath promised to them that love
him. And look, when you going through
problems
with with children and your family and
your loved ones, sometimes those things
may not be be grievious to deal with,
but they equipped you to make things
light on the earth, light work. Whatever
you deal with outside of that will be
light work for you. And there's one
other thing why it may be a challenge in
one way, there's beauty in another way
that you see in the same child that you
have that has autism. They they may be
heightened in other gifts that they
have. So my my suggestion biblically
speaking from what we read is to just be
patient and endure whatever trial you
dealing with in love. That's all I got.
That's right. Yes, sir.
>> Brother Dre, can can that James five
apply? If there be any sick among you,
let them pray and call for the elder.
Let them anoint them. Can that apply
there?
>> Absolutely, brother. Absolutely.
>> Yes.
>> Absolutely.
>> Because the Lord can heal.
>> But whether he heal or not, it's just
like the Hebrews said when they they
said, "We ain't gonna bow down to this
image. We know God can deliver, but
whether he deliver or not, we not gonna
bow down to this image. And the same way
with whatever situation that you find
yourself in that may be a trial, it's
about endurance and walking in love.
Look, while this may be autism for you,
for other people, there are things that
they're dealing with
that that is equal are in that range.
But be patient, endure affliction,
you know, walk in that spirit and the
Lord is going to deliver you because at
the end of the day in the kingdom, it
ain't going to be all that. So just be
faithful and keep walking.
>> That's right. Yep. And keep praying. As
we move on to our next question, Sister
De.
>> Yes. Next question. John Noel says,
"Holy Ghost." He wants you to explain
what is the Holy Ghost.
>> All right. Guest caller. Can you shed
some light on what is the Holy Ghost?
Okay,
guess caller, you with us?
>> Yeah.
>> All right. They want some explanation on
what is the Holy Ghost?
>> Well, you know that that
I'm going try to make this as simple as
possible. The one that they call God the
Holy Ghost, which is what was the third
part in the Godhead, is merely an angel.
Let's go and show you where God sent his
uh uh angel uh uh before Israel. Let's
go and do uh uh Exodus the 23rd chapter
and read verse 20 to 23.
Exodus 23
and verses 20 to 23 says, "Behold, I
send an angel before thee to keep thee
in the way, and to bring thee into the
place which I have prepared.
Beware of him, and obey his voice.
Provoke him not, for he will not pardon
your transgressions, for my name is in
him."
But if thou shalt in Uhhuh.
Go ahead.
>> But if thou shalt indeed obey his voice,
and do all that I speak, then I will be
an enemy unto thine enemies and an
adversary unto thine adversaries.
>> Okay? So he told them to do that. And
let's see if uh uh uh if Israel obeyed
him. Let's go into Isaiah the 63rd
chapter.
Read verses 9 and 10.
>> That is Isaiah the 63rd chapter
and verses 9 and 10. Correct.
>> Uhhuh.
>> It says in all their affliction he was
afflicted and the angel of his presence
saved them.
In his love and in his pity he redeemed
them and he bare them and carried them
all the days of old.
But they rebelled and vexed his holy
spirit. Therefore he was turned to be
their enemy and he fought against them.
See, to all angels are spirits. And the
ones that did not follow Satan, the Holy
Spirit.
And the ones that he sent to lead Israel
and he want and he and and he and what
he sent to teach Israel,
it is his angel. Let's go to Revelation
the first chapter, read verses 1 and
two.
>> Okay.
Revelation 1:es 1 and 2 says, "The
revelation of Jesus Christ, who gave
unto him to show unto his servants
things which must shortly come to pass."
And he sent and signified it by his
angel unto his servant John,
who bear record of the Uhhuh.
vision
>> who bear record of the word of God and
of the testimony of Jesus Christ and of
all things that he saw.
So now so the Lord always instructed his
people through his holy angels and the
angels that didn't follow Satan like I
said the holy spirits because the word
ghost is just slang for spirit.
Yep.
>> The one the message
is an angel. That's the Holy Ghost.
That's the one that Jesus said to the
experience that I go. If I go not, then
the comforter won't send won't come to
you. But if I go, I send you the
comforter, which is the Holy Ghost,
which is an angel.
And uh another part of it,
it's starting to show the Holy Ghost or
Holy Spirit is the word of God. Let's go
into uh uh St. John the 6th chapter.
Read verse 63.
Okay.
John 6 and verse 63 says,
"It is the spirit that quickenth. The
flesh profiteth nothing. The words that
I speak unto you, they are spirit and
they are life.
When you're full of the Holy Ghost,
you're full of the spirit of God.
That's why before that Jesus told these
people told us, he said, "Eat my flesh
and drink my blood."
If you eat my flesh and drink my blood,
you will have eternal life. And some of
his apostles said, "This is a hard
saying. Who can say it?" And that's what
he told him is the words that I speak.
They are spirit and they are life. So
when people talking about the Holy Ghost
that brings the word to you that's an
angel or either if you are full of the
Holy Ghost then that mean that you are
full of the word of God. Now the Holy
Spirit, the spirit come in many other
form but these are the main forms and if
you want to get the whole we have a
series that's called the spirit of God
in his many form and that will break
them down but if you can order that then
that will help you. The spirit of God in
his many forms all I have to say.
>> All right.
Thank you for that. as we continue to
move on.
>> Moving on. Um, Mr. and Mrs. Porter says,
"I am a nurse and sometimes I get
patients that want to be addressed as
the opposite sex due to them transition
for a lack of a better word. I'm in a
position where if I fail to address them
by their preferred status or pronoun,
I risk getting terminated. Can you share
any scriptures that can help guide me in
this situation?
>> Brother Julius,
>> the book says, "Love thy neighbor as thy
love thyself."
You are me working in the healthc care
field for 34 years. You are a
provider of medical care. You're a
professional nurse.
You're not a judge. Your job is to
provide health care, not to judge. You
don't have to agree because you like I
did. You also get patients that you
don't know who might be sinners. You
don't know what they did, but they might
be sinners or they may not be sinners.
But you deal with the public. You deal
with people who commit sins. Uh the
bottom line is to be a professional.
Call what's on the name on the chart
and provide the best medical care that
you can.
That is it. Whatever they doing and
whatever they transitioning to, that is
between them and God. You have to think
about it. Only become personal if you
make it personal. Think about providing
for yourself and your family. Do your
job. Let God be the judge, not you.
That's all I got.
>> All right,
we're gonna move on to our next question
with a time check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:38. Uh, Cassie Cassie
Lee says, "Next year is our first family
reunion cruise and is from Thursday
through Monday. Will this be a problem
in keeping the Sabbath when having
traditional family reunions?
>> All right. So, going on a cruise and
they concerned about keeping the
Sabbath. Guess caller.
>> Well, you know the book tell you that to
remember the Sabbath, they keep it holy.
>> Yep.
>> Now,
that's all I can offer you.
Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Straight to the point as we move on to
our next one.
>> Next one. Liz,
uh,
Liz asks, "Will there be only righteous
people in the wilderness?"
>> All right. When it comes to the
wilderness, will there be only righteous
in the wilderness? Guest call up.
Yeah, that's that's uh uh that question
uh kind of like I have
a a maybe
and then
no.
The one is a maybe is Revelation the
12th chapter. Let's go look at it.
Revelation 12th chapter. We're going to
read verse 6 and we're going to skip
down and read verse 14.
>> Okay. Revelation 12 and verse 6 says,
"And the woman fled into the wilderness
where she had a place prepared of God
that they should feed her there,
203 score days."
>> Verse mean that
>> that's that's six. The Lord going to
take this woman in the wilderness that's
talking about Israel. Well, if you and
that's spiritual and physical Israel in
there for protecting from the great
tribulation. Now verse 14.
14 says, "And to the woman were given
two wings of a great eagle that she
might fly into the wilderness and to her
place where she is nourished for a time
and times and half a time from the face
of the serpent."
Now, in this phase of the wilderness,
the people that's going, these are going
to be people that have understanding
and they've been found the word of God
and they understand the prophecies. So,
when they see the abomination standing
in the holy place, in other words, when
the build that temple over
there and the pope move in it, then they
will flee. And most of these un will be
righteous. Maybe all of them as far as
the man is concerned,
man's righteousness. But still that is a
maybe.
But then there's another time in the
wilderness when it be no. Not all people
will be righteous.
Let's go into Ezekiel the 20th chapter
and we're going to read from verse 33
38.
>> Okay. Ezekiel 20
vers
33-38
says
and that which cometh into your mind
shall not be at all that ye say we will
be as the heathen as the families of the
countries to serve wood and stone.
As I live, sayaeth the Lord God, surely
will a mighty hand, and with a stretched
out arm, and with fury poured out will I
rule over you.
And I will bring you out from the
people, and will gather you out of the
countries wherein ye are scattered, with
a mighty hand, and with a stretched out
arm, and with fury poured out.
and I will bring you into the wilderness
of the people, and there will I plead
with you face to face.
>> Like as I pleaded with your fathers in
the wilderness of the land of Egypt, so
will I plead with you, sayeth the Lord
God.
and I will cause you to pass under the
rod, and I will bring you into the bond
of the covenant,
and I will purge out from among you the
rebels, and them that transgress against
me. I will bring them forth out of the
country, where they sjjoin, and they
shall not enter into the land of Israel,
and ye shall know that I am the Lord."
Now in this case, most of the people
that the Lord going to take back to
Israel, that's after Jesus come back.
That's when he going to set his hand a
second time to cover Israel. And most of
them them are unrighteous. But that's
why he going to have them in the
wilderness for three and a half years.
And he is going to teach them. That's
what he mean. He going to bring them
into the bond of the covenant. And the
ones that will not uh uh adhere to Jesus
teaching, they're going to die in the
wilderness. They're not going to get
into the land just like our fathers
will. The Lord brought every Israelite
out of Egypt. Didn't leave one in there.
But every Israelite didn't get to the
promised land. In fact, all the people
that come out of Egypt from 20 years and
upward
died in the wilderness because they
rebelled against God. So no,
all people that go to the wilderness are
not going to be righteous, especially
after Jesus come back. And uh the ones
that flee before Jesus,
most likely all of them will be
righteous, especially once they get to
the wilderness because they're going to
have to have some understanding to know
that they got to flee to the wilderness.
>> Right?
>> So the first one is a maybe and the
second one, no, they're not going to all
be righteous. That's all I have to say.
>> All right, that was some good light
there. As we move on to our next
question,
>> next one. Sandra Allen says, "When will
the mark of the beast be instituted?
Will it be before tribulation start or
once tribulation have started?"
>> All right, Deborah. It looked like they
just left the word great tribulation off
of there. But yes, caller, will the mark
of the beast be before the great
tribulation or after the great
tribulation has started?
>> After it gets started. Go to Revelation
the 13th chapter.
and we're going to read verse
one.
Then we're going to skip down
and read verse 7 and then
skip down to verse 16. Revelation 13 and
1.
>> It says, "And I stood upon the sand of
the sea and saw a beast rise up out of
the sea having seven heads and 10 horns.
and upon his horns 10 crowns and upon
his heads the name of blasphemy.
>> Now this is talking about the European
Union. That's when it rise up cuz those
are the ones that's going to perpetrate
this great tribulation under the
tutorship of the pope. Now skip down to
seven.
>> And it was given unto him to make war
with the saints and to overcome them.
And power was given him over all
kindreds and tongues and nations
>> as during the great tribulation. Verse
16.
>> And he calls all both small and great,
rich and poor, free and bond to receive
a mark in their in their right hand or
in their foreheads.
So that starts after the great
tribulation
dies. They kind of p got you practicing
on it. Now what they going to do when
they call it? What's this? Uh um
>> Ash Wednesday
when they on Ash Wednesday they put a
mark on your forehead and in your right
hand that is represent the mark of the
beast. But they cannot do it and enforce
it and it won't get started until after
the great tribulation.
All right, thank you for that, Sister
Deborah. Next question. As time is a
ticking.
>> Yes. Uh, the Bayou Perspective asks in
Deuteronomy 24:16,
is this referring to spiritual death?
I'm asking because Ain and his family
were killed after he sinned and also
kids were killed throughout time after
nations sin against God.
>> All right, brother Jerome,
>> let's go read it. Deuteronomy 24
verse 16.
Okay. It says, "The father shall not be
put to death for the children, neither
shall the children be put to death for
the fathers. Every man shall be put to
death for his own sin."
>> Yeah, that's that's not talking about uh
spiritual death. That that's talking
about physical death.
Okay. But um
I I noticed you mentioned also in that
question uh about an
family were killed after he sin and also
kids were killed through the time after
the nation sinned
against God. Um, I want to show you
another example
um of what God said about a child when
his family uh were judged to be healed
and what God said about uh a child that
was uh part of that nation. Okay, let's
go to um First Kings 14
and we're going to read 10 through13.
Okay. It says,
"Therefore, behold, I will bring evil
upon the house of Jeroboam, and will cut
off from Jeroboam, him that pisseth
against the wall, and him that is shut
up and left in Israel, and will take
away the remnant of the house of
Jeroboam, as a man taketh away dung,
till it be all gone." Him that dieth of
Jeroboam in the city shall the dogs eat,
and him that dieth in the field shall
the fowls of the air eat, for the Lord
hath spoken it.
Arise thou, therefore, get thee to thine
own house, and when thy feet enter into
the city, the child shall die.
>> Mhm.
and all Israel shall mourn for him and
bury him. For he only of Jeroboam shall
come to the grave because in him there
is found some good thing toward the Lord
God of Israel in the house of Jeroboam.
>> Yeah. [clears throat] So even though
they all died according to God, even the
child,
the Lord said, "But I saw some good in
that child." You know, so even though
the Lord kill the children, see, the
Lord don't look on things the way we
look on them. So even though he killed
the the righteous,
you know, he know he going to raise them
from the dead, you know. So you know, I
I just wanted to share that with you,
you know, since you mentioned the
ancient piece. Anybody want to add
something, they can. I was going to add
1st Samuel 16-7. And you know the Lord,
the Lord lookth on the heart. You know,
he see things we don't see is what I'm
trying to say. All right.
>> Anybody want to add something, they can.
>> Yeah, you're right, Jerome. That's a
good system to have cuz according to the
statistics, they say 100 children die
every hour.
>> Wow.
>> We need the Lord to, you know, to have
his uh perfect program in place for
that. Okay. All right, brother. Thank
you for that. as we move on to our next
question.
>> Yes, we are now into tonight's Q&A for
Wednesday, November the 12, 2025.
>> Uh, a yes, a Thomas asked for
explanation on Isaiah 6
11-13
and 13- 16.
>> All right. So basically Isaiah 6 verse
11-6
>> through 16. Yes.
>> Okay. Why don't we go there and read
that
>> brother James
>> and when you get there we go open it up
to the panel. Isaiah 6 and pick it up at
verse
11.
>> 11.
>> It's only 13 and
>> yeah it's only 13. So we don't have a
13- 16. But let's pick it up there 11-13
and open that up to the passage.
>> Okay. It says, "Then said I, Lord, how
long?" And he answered, "Until the
cities be wasted without inhabitant, and
the houses without man, and the land be
utterly desolate.
And the Lord had removed men far away,
and there be a great forsaking in the
midst of the land.
But yet in it shall be a tenth, and it
shall return, and shall be eaten as a
teal tree, and as an oak, whose
substance is in them. When they cast
their leaves, so the holy seed shall be
the substance thereof.
>> All right, let's open that up to the
pal.
Well, all they said is that the Lord got
tired of Israel. And when he got tired
of Israel and Judah, he took down the
righteous and the unrighteous. But it
let you know that all the may going to
get killed. You still going to have some
that go into captivity and they going to
be returned.
It's all the same.
All right, thank you for that. As we
continue to move on to our next one,
>> uh the next one, please explain what
constitutes or what are the components
of a biblical marriage.
>> What are the components or what makes up
as they would say what is a biblical
marriage? Holy matrimony between a male
and a female with the marriage license.
>> Anybody else?
>> And then once you get into marriage, you
just have to remember to keep God's
commandments.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Is to Israel, you know, I'm married to
you.
So,
>> you have to keep commandments and don't
go messing with no
out other God. So the male and female
keep God's commandments and don't go
around messing around outside of the
marriage. And you have to practice love.
And what is love? Keeping the
commandments.
>> Yep. And
>> you do your part, you do her part. And
don't defraud one another.
>> That's right. And also if you like
further explanation on that, we have a
lesson for that also called marriage and
family conduct.
>> Family conduct.
>> All right, we're going to keep moving.
>> Moving on. Pauline R asks, "What does
Proverbs 18 verse1 mean? Does it mean
you will get wisdom and when you
separate yourself seeking wisdom?"
Proverbs 18 and1.
>> Yes.
>> All right. Let's read that, brother. And
let's open that also up to the path.
Proverbs 18 verse1 says th though
through desire a man having separated
himself seeketh and intermetaleth
with all wisdom.
>> All right. open to the path
because James read that verse two too
because it's letting you know that a
fool have no delight in understanding
but that first verse is good for a man
that's seeking the wisdom and knowledge
of God. Read to
>> a fool have no delight in understanding
but that his heart may discover itself.
>> Mhm.
Well, it tell you uh uh said uh uh uh
who see if I can think of scripture say
you know the fear of the Lord is the
beginning of wisdom.
>> Wisdom that's
>> but a fool
ate knowledge.
Somebody pull it up right quick.
>> Psalm 111.
>> Yeah. You know said wisdom of God is the
beginning of wisdom.
>> All right. Search search mode for that.
We'll find that shortly.
>> Yeah. Psalms 111 I think verse 10.
>> Psalms 111
and also Proverbs 1 and 22.
>> Yeah, I think the one is in Proverbs.
>> Proverbs 9 and 10.
Proverbs uh
>> Oh yeah,
>> let me go here.
>> Yeah, that's it. Let's go.
>> Yeah. Proverbs uh Proverbs uh 9:10 says,
"The fear of the Lord is the beginning
of wisdom, and the knowledge of the holy
is understanding."
>> But you can skip down that same chapter,
but you you should see But fools hate
knowledge.
>> Yeah. Let's see here.
Let's see.
>> Searching for that one.
>> Hey, knowledge is is talking about the
simple
>> Proverbs 1 and 7 James.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> It says the fear of the Lord is the
beginning of knowledge, but fools
despise wisdom and instruction.
Mhm.
>> So you know, so all that is saying is
that foolish people don't they don't
want to know no knowledge and you you
know they hung up time think they are
Christians and you tried reading this
Bible to I don't want to hear that.
>> Yeah.
>> That's a person that hate college.
That's a foolish person.
>> Yeah.
>> You was written God.
>> That's all it's saying. Yeah. And and
James read 22 while we there.
>> Okay.
How long ye simple ones will ye love
simplicity and the scorners delight in
their scorning and fools hate knowledge.
>> That's what I was That's what I was
looking for. Okay. That's all they're
saying in some that fools hate
knowledge.
>> Yeah.
>> They don't want it.
>> Wow.
Okay. Hope you
That's call.
>> I want to keep it simple. All you got to
do is believe on Christ and you going to
be saved.
>> But when the young man Jesus what what
should he do to get saved? He told him
to keep the commandments.
>> Yeah, that's what he told him.
>> But uh so the whole thing is how can you
believe only God if you you have never
heard?
>> Right.
>> Yep.
>> That's all. All right.
Okay. Uh, Sister Deborah, one more
question and we're going to end our
program.
>> All right. Uh, Shanquilla A Joby says,
"Jesus cast out evil spirits recognizing
they were not part of people." He gives
Luke 8 verse30.
He wants to know is envy, bitterness, or
selfishness signs to watch for? And if
so, why do so many act like these are
their personalities?
>> All right. Anything that's contrary to
what thus says the Lord is always good
to watch out for. But he said Luke 8
and30, correct?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. dealing with legion. So go ahead,
brother James, and then let's open that
up to the panel for our final question
of the evening.
>> Luke 8:30 says, "And Jesus asked him,
saying, what is thy name? And he said,
Legion because many devils were entered
into him."
>> That's him. I don't mean a person that's
might be mean or evil sometime or talk
crazy is possessed by evil spirit.
>> Right.
>> That just that just mean they could have
bad personality could be having a bad
day. Amen.
>> But to say a person is possessed by an
evil spirit, nobody nobody can can make
that claim unless you passing judgment
on somebody and the Lord tell you judge
not because the same judge that you
judge but you judge you going to be
judged by.
>> That's right.
>> Right.
>> That's all.
>> Yep. So we hope that brought some light
to you on our last question of the
evening. Time check, Sister Deborah.
901.
>> All right, 901. We want to thank
everybody from all around the world who
sent in those questions. We thank you
and we'd like to say if you submitted a
question and we didn't get to it, please
don't resubmit it. Sister Deborah, take
it. Put it in rotation and we will
address that question next week. So,
until we all come together again, we ask
you please be safe, be blessed, stay
prayed up, and may the Lord have mercy
on us all as brother James closes us
out. Our
Father, which art in heaven, hallowed be
thy name. Thy kingdom come, thy will be
done in earth as it is in heaven. Give
us this day our daily bread. And forgive
us our debts as we forgive our debts.
>> And lead us not into temptation, but
deliver us from evil. For thine is the
kingdom and the power and the glory
forever. In Jesus name we pray.